Guide to the Ruth Ann Overbeck papers & Washington Perspectives, Inc. records, 1663-2007 MS2032
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Ruth Ann Overbeck papers & Washington Perspectives, Inc. records
1663-2007
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Overbeck, Ruth Ann
MS2032
31 Linear Feet
Collection documents the breath and depth of work done by Ruth Ann Overbeck as a historian in D.C. for thirty years. The collection has material for many projects from house histories for individual homeowners to a survey of the Upper Cardozo Columbia Heights neighborhood with oral histories and surveys of buildings such as the Tivoli Theater.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Robert Hughes, 1998.
Historical or Biographical Note
Ruth Ann Overbeck founded Washington Perspectives, Inc. (W.P.I.) in 1975. The purpose of the organization as stated in the articles of incorporation was " to conduct research, plan, and implement various cultural, historical, social and education programs, including, but not limited to, conducting guided tours, preparing historical and other reports, and to carry out any other activities within the general scope of the above." The diversity of projects within this collection demonstrates that the firm achieved this purpose.
Most of the success of W.P.I. is attributable to Ruth Ann Overbeck. Ruth Ann first visited Washington, D.C. in the 1950s while still in high school in Texas. She attended college in Texas, but always planned to return to Washington. She did this in 1968, purchasing a house on Capitol Hill, and living in that home until her death in April 2000.
Ruth Ann's work as a historic preservation consultant and as the president of W.P.I. earned her a reputation as a thoughtful and dedicated scholar. She wrote numerous articles and worked on many reports for the D.C. government and community agencies. She conducted numerous walking tours of D.C., founded the preservation trust, a façade easement trust, and served on many boards including Friendship House Association, Inc. and Capitol Hill Restoration Society. One of her final acts as an historian was to be interviewed for an oral history project about her experiences researching, working, and living in the Capitol Hill neighborhood. Ruth Ann had planned to write a book about Capitol Hill, but did not have the opportunity. The oral history project was her way to record her vast knowledge of Capitol Hill and Washington D.C. history and make it accessible to researchers.
The donation made in April 2000, followed by another accretion June 2003, to the George Washington University of these historical records represents Ruth Ann and Robert Hughes' efforts to accomplish the same objective. This collection and the work that will certainly come from its use by researchers is a fitting tribute to Ruth Ann Overbeck and allows her contribution to Washington history to continue.
Collection Scope and Content
The material in this collection is a terrific representation of the breadth and depth of work done by Ruth Ann Overbeck as a historian in D.C. for thirty years. The collection has material for many projects from house histories for individual homeowners to a survey of the Upper Cardozo Columbia Heights neighborhood with oral histories and surveys of buildings such as the Tivoli Theater.
The collection will prove to be extremely useful for researchers exploring topics related to Washington, D.C. history. The D.C. Research Subseries within the Research Materials Series primarily includes notes, citations, and photocopies gathered by Ruth Ann and other W.P.I. employees for specific research projects. Often times the final product especially the house histories is included in the folders.
The collection does not contain much information about the administrative side of W.P.I. Series VII: W.P.I. Administration Records does have a small amount of financial records, but it is clearly only a sampling. The research records, however, do provide a picture of the types of projects undertaken by W.P.I. and the methods and efforts used by Ruth Ann Overbeck and the other W.P.I. historians.
The bulk dates for the collection material range from approximately 1970 through 1995. The collection measures 46 clamshells, 1 oversize box, and 23 map tubes. The total size is approximately 28 linear feet. The collection is arranged in seven series. Within each series the material is arranged alphabetically by folder title. The house histories are arranged by address.
Collection Organization
Organized into seven series: Biographical Information; Brochures; Graphics; Maps, plats, and blueprints; Publications; Research Material and Washington Perspectives Incorporation (W.P.I.) Administrative Records.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transfer from Tanya Edwards Beauchamp, 2019 February (Accession 2019.006).
These records came to Tanya from Robert Hughes the donor of the Ruth Ann Overbeck papers. In February 2019 Tanya Edwards Beauchamp tranferred two large boxes of materials related to the Anacostia Park history project Ruth Ann Overbeck was working on, but was unable to finish due to illness and ultimately her death. These records are in boxes 69-73.
Blueprints (reprographic copies); Maps; Historians; Transportation maps; Historic preservation; Washington (D.C.) -- History; Washington (D.C.); Plats (maps); Maryland; Washington Perspectives, Inc.; Overbeck, Ruth Ann
- Biographical information, Circa 1970-1995; MS2032 Series 1; 0.25 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  This series has one file with material about Ruth Ann Overbeck including her resume, articles about her, and some information about the W.P.I. and graphics director Robert Hughes.
  - Biographical Information about Ruth Ann Overbeck, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Brochures, Circa 1983; MS2032 Series 2; 0.25 Linear feet
  This series contains brochures about different activities in the District of Columbia and various states primarily on the East Coast.
  - District of Columbia, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Maryland, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Pennsylvania, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Virginia, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - DE, TX, CT, NY, NJ, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Standards for Rehabilitation" from Secretary of the Interior, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Graphics, 1984-1992; MS2032 Series 3; 2.25 Linear feet
  The series has images of District related topics and others from outside the D.C. area. Many of the topics within this series are also represented in Series VI and should be used together. In an effort to make the complimentary nature between the two series easier, the subseries within this series matches the subseries in Series VI.
  - District of Columbia Houses: 441 4th St. NE, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - District of Columbia Houses: 129 6th St. NE, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - District of Columbia Houses: 211 8th St. NE "before", undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - District of Columbia Houses: 1836 16th St. NW, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - District of Columbia Houses: 1919 16th St. NW, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - District of Columbia Houses: 134 30th St. NW, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - District of Columbia Houses: 203 3rd St. SE Jan., 1981 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - District of Columbia Houses: 521 4th St. SE (and 746 7th St. SE), undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - District of Columbia Houses: 734 7th St. SE (and 746 7th St. SE), undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - District of Columbia Houses: 735 8t ST. SE, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - District of Columbia Houses: 226 9th St. SE (and 6th St. SE), undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - District of Columbia Houses: 136 12th St. SE, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - District of Columbia Houses: 154 12th St. SE (and 148 12th St. SE), undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - District of Columbia Houses: 315 12th St. SE (and 806 D. St. SE and 234 11th St. NE) Jan., 1989 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - District of Columbia Houses: 660 block Maryland Ave. NE (and interiors 615 Maryland Ave NE), undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - District of Columbia Houses: 615 Maryland Ave. NE (and 647 East Capitol St. and 632 Mass. Ave. NE), undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - District of Columbia Houses: 226 Massachusetts Ave. NE, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - District of Columbia Houses: 632 Massachusetts Ave. NE "before" (see also box 2 folder 10), undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - District of Columbia Houses: 632 Massachusetts Ave. NE TRA appeal case, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - District of Columbia Houses: 632 Massachusetts Ave. NE (and 317 C St. NE and 324 Mass. Ave. and 650 Independence Ave.), undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - District of Columbia Houses: 1768 & 1770 Church St. NW, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - District of Columbia Houses: 642 East Capital St. alley zoning shots, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - District of Columbia Houses: 2115 N St. NW Historic Preservation Certification Application, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - District of Columbia Houses: 1727 P St. NW, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - District of Columbia Houses: 620 C. St. SE (and 435 10th St. NE), undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - District of Columbia Houses: 1237 C. St. SE, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - District of Columbia Houses: 806 D St. SE (see also box 2 folder 8), undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - District of Columbia Houses: 1218 G St. SE, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - District of Columbia Houses: G St. and 8th after the fire March 1986 (and 308 East Capital St. 310 East Capital St. and 1614 19th St. NW), undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - District of Columbia Houses: 642 Independence Ave. SE, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - District of Columbia Houses: 1217 Massachusetts Ave SE, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - District of Columbia Houses: 1312 Massachusetts Ave SE, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - District of Columbia Houses: 642 East Capital St. stained glass window, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - District of Columbia Houses: 647 East Capital St. basement unit interior and Lewis, DE 647 East Capitol St (see box 2 folder 10), 1984 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - District of Columbia Houses: 1206 East Capital St. [not sure of this identification], undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - District of Columbia Houses: Unidentified photographs interior and exterior, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - District of Columbia Houses: Unidentified houses Preservation Trust, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Topics: Blacks in the Arts Tanya Beauchamps reception, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Topics: CHRS house tour, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Topics: Deanwood, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Topics: Eastern Market Aug. 13, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Topics: Friendship House, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Topics: Grace Church Condominiums, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Topics: Marine Barracks, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Topics: Preservation Trust Exhibit, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Topics: Preservation Trust Façade Review March, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Topics: Preservation Trust Façade Review April 20, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Topics: Preservation Trust Façade Review May 11, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Topics: Sears building Bladensburg Rd. NE, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Topics: Southeast Neighborhood House August, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Topics: Treasury Building, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Topics: Upper Cardozo Community Program, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Topics: Washington D.C. Scenes, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Topics: Washington Seawall, 1985-1988 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Topics outside D.C.: Hilly Grove, Canada A. Beall, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Topics outside D.C.: House History Book Canada June-July, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Topics outside D.C.: Lewes, Delaware Preservation Trust, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Topics outside D.C.: Louisa Kentucky Ashland Oil Field, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Topics outside D.C.: Ashland and Phillipi (see also box 5 folder 6), undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Topics outside D.C.: Yatesville Lake, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Topics outside D.C.: Cross Manor, St. Mary's County Maryland April 7, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    General note
    There is more material related to Cross Manor and Overbeck's research of that property in Series 6 boxes 67, 68, and 69. These boxes arrived at a later date and were not part of the original processing.
  - Topics outside D.C.: Lower Bank Bridge, New Jersey, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Topics outside D.C.: Pomeroy's Building Harrisburg, PA, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Topics outside D.C.: Alexandria Canal, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Topics outside D.C.: Federal Hill Clark County, VA, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Topics outside D.C.: 800 Caroline St. Fredericksburg, VA, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Topics outside D.C.: Gainesville, VA project, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Topics outside D.C.: McLean, Virginia Project, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Topics outside D.C.: Waterford, VA property, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Topics outside D.C.: Lost River barnes and houses, 1990-1992 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Topics outside D.C.: Louisa/Phillipi/ Lost River West Virginia, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Topics outside D.C.: West Virginia Mill Restoration, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Topics outside D.C.: West Virginia Slides--might be Petersburg, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Topics outside D.C.: Petersburg, West Virginia George Judy Homeplace (only Xeroxes), undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Topics outside D.C.: Phillipi West Virginia and Louisa, KT (see also box 4 folder 9), undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Topics outside D.C.: Ripley, West Virginia, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Topics outside D.C.: Thurmond, West Virginia train depot, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Topics outside D.C.: Pauline Crumbe, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Topics outside D.C.: Cymrot, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Topics outside D.C.: Friedland Project, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Topics outside D.C.: House Histories Book, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Topics outside D.C.: Ruth Ann Overbeck portraits, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Topics outside D.C.: Unidentified, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Maps, plats, and blueprints, 1792-1990; MS2032 Series 4; 4 Linear feet
  This series includes maps, plats, and blueprints collected as part of broader research efforts. The maps often match the topics in Series VI and were most likely products of that research. The processor placed these items in a separate series because of the storage needs of rolled and oversize items. File units 44-66 in this series are map tubes holding rolled items.
  - Small folded maps and plats: City of Washington, 1792 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Small folded maps and plats: Generalized Land Use Map 1-4, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Small folded maps and plats: Historic District Maps, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Small folded maps and plats: Meridian Hill Subdivision Plat, 1867 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Small folded maps and plats: Street car map, 1925 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Small folded maps and plats: Wards, 1801-1871 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Eastern Market, undated (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Dupont Circle Historic District, 1977 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - James Creek Valley Trunk Sewer n.d., undated (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - U.S. Naval Gun Factory Quarters B, 1950 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Naval Observatory Quarters D improvements, 1965 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Naval Observatory Married Officers Quarters plumbing and heating, 1946 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - 14th St. Urban Renewal Area, 1980 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Unidentified map -Plat of D.C., undated (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Aerial Maps, undated (Tube 44)
  - Map, 1857 (Tube 45)
  - Plats, undated (Tube 46)
  - Topographical, undated (Tube 47)
  - Anacostia Bridge -- Potomac River to Anacostia Bridge, Potomac River Virginia Channel, Washington Channel, 1947-1953 (Tube 48)
  - Eastern Market and National Park Service highway 1930 and Shaw School Urban Renewal Area, 1973 (Tube 49)
  - James Creek, undated (Tube 50)
  - Upper Cardozo Columbia Heights, undated (Tube 51)
  - Upper Cardozo Columbia Heights, undated (Tube 52)
  - Washington Navy Yard, undated (Tube 53)
  - Washington Seawall, undated (Tube 54)
  - Friendship House, 1937 (Tube 55)
  - Friendship House, 1937 (Tube 56)
  - Friendship House, 1937 (Tube 57)
  - Friendship House, 1937 (Tube 58)
  - Friendship House, 1937 (Tube 59)
  - Friendship House plumbing, 1937 (Tube 60)
  - Friendship House mechanical and electrical improvements, 1988 (Tube 61)
  - Friendship House, 1969-1990 (Tube 62)
  - Friendship House, undated (Tube 63)
  - Friendship House, undated (Tube 64)
  - Cross Manor, undated (Tube 65)
  - Elk Creek Jackson County, WV and Residence of Grace Anne Dorney St. Mary's Co. MD and Lusk Washington D.C. Historic Preservation map, undated (Tube 66)
- Publications, Circa 1974-1993; MS2032 Series 5; 1.5 Linear feet
  This series includes articles, newspaper clippings, and periodicals collected by Ruth Ann Overbeck and W.P.I. historians.
  - Articles: 100 Years of Capital Traction: The Story of Streetcars in the Nation's Capital" by LeRoy O. King. Jr., undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Articles: "A Tale of Two Towns: Georgetown and Washington" by Martin K. Gordon, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Articles: "Autobiography of Harold E. Erwin Years 1903-1985", undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Articles: "Alexander "Boss" Shepard", undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Articles: City design articles, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Articles: Contemporary comments reports and descriptions of D.C., undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Articles: Deed restrictions 1790-1900 A Method of Controlling the Built Environment, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Articles: "In the Capitol's Shadow: Two Neighborhoods" by Keith Melder, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Articles: History Businesses, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Articles: History of D.C., undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Articles: History of D.C., undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Articles: "Homework and Nineteenth-Century West Virginia Women" by Barbara J. Howe, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Articles: "In the Shadow of the Dome" International Teamster June, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Articles: Larry Myer's Papers, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Articles: "The Monogalia Story: A Bicentennial History", 1974 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Articles: Review of Houses and Homes: Exploring Their History, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Articles: "This Was the Potomac River" by Frederick Tilp, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Articles: Underground Railroad, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Articles: Articles about Virginia topics, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Newspaper articles: Articles written by Paul O. Cardwell, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Periodicals: Cultural Resources Management, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Periodicals: Cultural Resources Management (CRM) nos. 1-4, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Periodicals: Cultural Resources Management nos. 6-8 nos. 1-2, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Periodicals: Cultural Resources Management nos. 5&7 no. 3, 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Periodicals: Cultural Resources Management Bulletin vol. 12 no. 3, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Periodicals: Folklife Center News American Folklife Center Library of Congress, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Periodicals: The Institute for the History of Technology and Industrial Archaeology Vol. 1 No. 1 Winter, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Periodicals: Local Preservation Issue paper: Conservation Districts, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Periodicals: Preservation Briefs, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Periodicals: Preservation Tech Notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Periodicals: National Register Bulletin No. 29,30,41,42, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Periodicals: The Smithsonian Associate (not inclusive), 1975-1981 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Periodicals: The Smithsonian Associate (not inclusive), 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Publications on D.C.: The Anacostia Story 1608/1930, undated (Box 7A, Folder 1)
  - Publications on D.C.: Old Anacostia, undated (Box 7A, Folder 2)
  - Publications on D.C.: Anacostia Conserved, 1979 (Box 7A, Folder 3)
  - Publications on D.C.: Design Guide for the Exterior Rehabilitation of Buildings in Old Anacostia, undated (Box 7A, Folder 4)
  - Publications on D.C.: Dumbarton Oaks, undated (Box 7A, Folder 5)
  - Publications on D.C.: Continuity Through Change: LeDroit Park by Ronald M. Johnson, undated (Box 7A, Folder 6)
  - Publications on D.C.: LeDroit Park Conserved, 1979 (Box 7A, Folder 7)
  - Publications on D.C.: Sumner School Building; Application by the Board of Education of the District of Columbia to the Joint Committee on Landmarks of the National Capital to Designate Sumner School Building as a Historic Landmark, undated (Box 7A, Folder 8)
  - Publications on historic preservation: Access to Historic Buildings for the Disabled: Suggestions for Planning and Implementation, 1980 (Box 7A, Folder 9)
  - Publications on historic preservation: Accommodation of Disabled Visitors at Historic Sites in the National Park System, 1983 (Box 7A, Folder 10)
  - Publications on historic preservation: Cultural Landscapes: Rural Historic Districts in the National Park System, 1984 (Box 7A, Folder 11)
  - Publications on historic preservation: Defending Our Heritage, 1991 (Box 7A, Folder 12)
  - Publications on historic preservation: Design Guidelines Handbook for Historic Preservation, 1979 (Box 7A, Folder 13)
  - Publications on historic preservation: Federal Tax Provisions to Encourage Rehabilitation of Historic Buildings: An Assessment of Their Effect, 1979 (Box 7A, Folder 14)
  - Publications on historic preservation: Guide to Resources Used in Historic Preservation Research, undated (Box 7A, Folder 15)
  - Publications on historic preservation: Legacy Resource Management Program, undated (Box 7A, Folder 16)
  - Publications on historic preservation: Rehabilitating Historic Hotels Peabody Hotel, Memphis TN, 1980 (Box 7A, Folder 17)
  - Publications outside D.C.: An Architectural Study of Some Log Structures in the Area of the Yatesville Lake Lawrence County, Kentucky, 1978 (Box 7B, Folder 1)
  - Publications outside D.C.: Historic Documentation and Archaeological Potential of Nine Historic Sites in the Proposed Yatesville Reservoir, Lawrence County, Kentucky, 1987 (Box 7B, Folder 2)
  - Publications on D.C.: The Anacostia Story 1608/1930, undated (Box 7A, Folder 1)
  - Publications on D.C.: Old Anacostia, undated (Box 7A, Folder 2)
  - Publications on D.C.: Anacostia Conserved, 1979 (Box 7A, Folder 3)
  - Publications on D.C.: Design Guide for the Exterior Rehabilitation of Buildings in Old Anacostia, undated (Box 7A, Folder 4)
  - Publications on D.C.: Dumbarton Oaks, undated (Box 7A, Folder 5)
  - Publications on D.C.: Continuity Through Change: LeDroit Park by Ronald M. Johnson, undated (Box 7A, Folder 6)
  - Publications on D.C.: LeDroit Park Conserved, 1979 (Box 7A, Folder 7)
  - Publications on D.C.: Sumner School Building; Application by the Board of Education of the District of Columbia to the Joint Committee on Landmarks of the National Capital to Designate Sumner School Building as a Historic Landmark, undated (Box 7A, Folder 8)
  - Publications on historic preservation: Access to Historic Buildings for the Disabled: Suggestions for Planning and Implementation, 1980 (Box 7A, Folder 9)
  - Publications on historic preservation: Accommodation of Disabled Visitors at Historic Sites in the National Park System, 1983 (Box 7A, Folder 10)
  - Publications on historic preservation: Cultural Landscapes: Rural Historic Districts in the National Park System, 1984 (Box 7A, Folder 11)
  - Publications on historic preservation: Defending Our Heritage, 1991 (Box 7A, Folder 12)
  - Publications on historic preservation: Design Guidelines Handbook for Historic Preservation, 1979 (Box 7A, Folder 13)